Gelawdios Bahlibi Abraham

Email: gelawbah@gmail.com | Phone: 251911383104

Address: House No. 387/03, Arada sub-city, woreda 01, Addis Ababa region, Ethiopia

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gelawdios-bahlibi | Website: nan

Date of Birth: 1984-05-05 00:00:00 | Gender: Male | Nationality: Ethiopian

Profile Summary

Gelawdios is a Monitoring, Evaluation & Learning lead with a total of 15 years of practical working experience; coordinating in projects on Fintech, eCommerce, Tourism, Apiculture, Rural, and Urban Agriculture, Environmental protection and pollution control over the years. Gelawdios has strong people skills and the capacity for simultaneously facilitating multiple responsibilities and priorities without compromising quality. He has consistently exhibited coordination qualities while enhancing teamwork to achieve stated goals. He has extensive experience working with a diverse range of internal and external stakeholders, maintaining a smooth relationship with partners, donors, government officials, smallholder farmers, and the senior management team. Gelawdios has a solid track record of designing different logical frameworks, monitoring, and evaluation tools, preparing and delivering different levels of training, plan and lead various Survey's, strategic planning, and negotiation skills to successfully implement projects while operating within time and budget. Gelawdios invested most of his time in Administrating and managing monitoring and evaluation data of different projects focusing on outgrowing farm schism and contract farming.

Work Experience

Location: Addis Ababa

Responsibilities: i am still working in Kifiya financial technology PLC.Support the MERL manager in developing and implementing the M&E plan for the access to finance program. Support the alignment of MEL frameworks with program objectives, donor requirements, and industry best practices. Design and conduct surveys to collect data on the program's participants, activities, and outcomes. Clean, analyze, and interpret data collected through surveys, focus groups, and other data collection methods. Prepare reports on the program's progress and impact, including dashboards, infographics, and written reports. Coordinate and support the planning and implementation of program evaluations and impact assessments. Contribute to the development of knowledge products, such as reports, briefs, and learning materials. Design evaluation methodologies and tools, including baseline and end line surveys, to measure program effectiveness and impact. Provide training and technical assistance to program staff

and partners on MEL concepts, tools and methodologies. Support program teams in data collection, analysis, and reporting activities. Work with the MERL manager and other team members to ensure that the program's M&E system is effective and efficient. Representing the program at conferences and events on M&E.

Business development associate at Insight Consults PLC (2020-06-01 00:00:00 - 2021-02-28 00:00:00)

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Responsibilities: Analyze actual and predicted developments in the industry, trends, market conditions and rivals 'activities with a view to determining potential opportunities. Contact potential clients, build relationships to have a clearer picture of what they need and how the company's offerings can solve their problems. Create parameters, measure and analyze appropriate inputs to assess the effectiveness of business development plans. Perform various kinds of surveys and studies. Attend high profile events and any other networking occasions on behalf of the organization to build a network. Prepare routine reports on business development activities undertaken, their status, and results for management reporting. Maintain relationship with customers to enhance customer satisfaction and identify areas for further selling to customers. Participate in developing business planning and business measures in conformity with general corporate strategy the Company.

Managing Director at Stantech Travel Agency (2019-09-01 00:00:00 - 2020-03-31 00:00:00)

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Responsibilities: Analyze upcoming trends and competitive surroundings and market dynamics to identify future growth possibilities. Interact with possible customers and develop their interest in understanding how the company's products fit their needs. Maintain monitoring and measurement of specific metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of proposed business development and marketing activities. Carry out a variety of surveys and research activities. Travel for and contribute to exhibitions and conferences to promote the company and build contacts. Prepare and supply the management with periodic updates on the status of the business development plan and its implementation. Keep in touch with clients after the sale to ensure satisfaction and look for additional sales opportunities. Assist in developing business policies and activities of the organization that promote the strategic vision of the organization.

Farmer Accounts Data Officer at Technoserve Ethiopia (2019-01-01 00:00:00 - 2019-09-30 00:00:00)

Location: Addis Ababa

Responsibilities: Supervise the development and upkeep of the Farmer Accounts Platform and other databases. Oversee data collection and entry for both the Farmer Accounts Database and the Enterprise Database. Assist in the digitalization of farmer and enterprise accounts, as well as their aggregation. Support external partners in effectively utilizing the Contract Farming Database Platform by

providing training for them and farmer organizations, and by coordinating with external partners while troubleshooting any issues that arise. Configure tablets to access monitoring content (training observations, evaluations, aggregations, etc.) from the online system and ensure synchronization with it. Monitor the online tablet-based training observations, evaluations, and aggregations. Assist in the design and implementation of evaluation surveys, including developing the work plan and budget for these surveys, and facilitating training related to survey processes. Support the management of evaluation survey implementation, overseeing data collection, ensuring data quality, and conducting data analysis and report writing. Ensure survey quality assurance using built-in algorithms (e.g., SurveyCTO and Google Sheets). Respond to data requests and customized report requests promptly. Implement the project's Learning Agenda in collaboration with the Project Manager and Senior MEL Coordinator.

M & E Administrator at Technoserve Ethiopia (2015-07-01 00:00:00 - 2018-12-31 00:00:00)

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Responsibilities: Generate and apply relevant survey tools to international programs, gathering appropriate information. Make certain that the data is correctly entered as well as any databases connected to that program are updated efficiently. Methodically evaluate the activities of the project against the targets and objectives set out in the work plans of the project. Go to the field to monitor the implementation of the program and conduct qualitative assessments. Provide assistance in the preparation and implementation of evaluation designs of individual projects including but not limited to formative and summative evaluations. Help design evaluation plans in regard to the detailed timeframe and budget. Program monitoring reporting, working with all partners on a successful completion of the activity; Defining the success of the program, challenges and lessons learned. Prepare data for the allocation of donor reports as well as any other communications with stakeholders. Conducting and supporting M &E training for staff or project partners or stakeholders as appropriate. Establish a practice of measuring and accounting for effectiveness and learning within the institution. Work jointly with program staff, partners and beneficiaries to ensure that M & E is practical and fulfills program objectives. Lead focus group discussions and other discussion forums with sampling communities to draw lessons on the program. Observe ethical considerations as well as data collection standards during the data collection process. Interact with the beneficiaries and identify trends within the populace and give practical solutions to the program. Help to promote the use of such evidence within the decision-making processes / structures in the institution. Adhere to organizational and donor policies that are specific to M & E. Utilize M&E software and tools for data management and analysis.

Education

Master's Degree in BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA)

Institution: LEADSTAR COLLEGE OF MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP | Dates: 2018-01-01 00:00:00 - 2021-03-0

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Bachelor's Degree in Managment

Institution: Arba Minch University | Dates: 2012-07-01 00:00:00 - 2016-08-29 00:00:00

Location: Arba Minch, Ethiopia

Bachelor's Degree in Dry land crops and horticultural science

Institution: Mekelle university | Dates: 2004-11-11 00:00:00 - 2008-07-19 00:00:00

Location: Mekelle, Ethiopia

Certification/Online Courses in Project Monitoring and Evaluation

Institution: Addis Ababa university | Dates: 2024-01-13 00:00:00 - 2024-02-03 00:00:00

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Certification/Online Courses in Agribusiness Marketing Ecosystem Alliance

Institution: International Finance corporation | Dates: 2017-10-16 00:00:00 - 2017-10-21 00:00:00

Location: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Skills & Tools

ODK survey tool, Kubo, survey CTO, CommCare, Questionnaire development, Scripting, Deploying, Data quality check, Data analysis and Reporting.

Languages

Amharic, Tigrigna, English

Awards & Certificates

Certificate of Appreciation from Stantech Tourism (2020-02-17 00:00:00)

Description: Recognized for significantly increasing company sales through strategic outreach and client engagement efforts.